So what is this data analysis process?
那么 数据分析过程是怎样的呢？
We broke it up into five steps: question,
我们把过程拆成五步 提出问题、
wrangle, explore, draw conclusions and communicate.
整理数据、探索数据、得出结论以及进行交流
This process will help you understand,
这个过程能帮你理解、
explore and use your data
探索并巧妙地运用数据
intelligently so that you make the most of the information you're given.
从而最大限度地利用你得到的信息
Whether you're building your reporting dashboard,
无论你是要制作仪表盘报表、
analyzing A-B test results or doing more advanced analysis with machine learning and AI.
分析 A/B 测试结果 还是用机器学习和人工智能进行更深入的分析 都需要这个过程
Let's see what each step is about.
我们来看看每一步骤具体内容吧
The data analysis process always starts with asking questions.
数据分析过程总是以提出问题开始的
Sometimes, you're already given a data set and
有时 你是先有了数据集
glance over it to figure out good questions to ask.
这时你会大致看一遍 想好要问的问题
Other times, your questions come first,
有时 你是先想到问题
which will determine what kinds of data you'll gather later.
再根据问题决定接下来要收集什么数据
In both cases, you should be thinking: what am I trying to find out?
无论处于哪种情况 你都应该想 我想找出的是什么？
Is there a problem I'm trying to solve?
有我想要解决的问题吗？
For example, what are the characteristics of students who pass their projects?
比如 通过项目的学生都有什么特点？
How can I better stock my store with products people want to buy?
我要怎么优化存货结构 给自己商店存下人们想买的货物？
In the real world, you often deal with multiple sets of massive amounts of data,
在现实世界里 你经常要处理多个庞大的数据集
all in different forms.
还是类型完全不同的数据集
The right questions can really help you focus on relevant parts of
准确的问题能真正让你聚焦与问题有关的那部分数据
your data and direct your analysis towards meaningful insights.
为分析提供方向 助你获得有意义的见解
In this course, we're going to focus on use cases with one set of
本课程将重点放在某个数据集的使用案例上
data and practice posing
并练习提出问题
relevant and interesting questions that lead to valuable results.
提出的问题既要有趣、有相关性 还要能引导出富有价值的结果
Once you have your questions,
等你提出了问题
you'll need to wrangle your data to help you answer them.
你就需要整理数据
By that, I mean making sure you have all the data you need in great quality.
我的意思是 对于你手头所有的必要数据 你要保证它们的质量
There are three parts to this step.
整理步骤分为三个部分
First, you gather your data.
首先 收集数据
If you are already given that data,
如果你已经有了数据
then all you need to do is open it,
那么你要做的就是打开数据
like importing it into a Jupyter Notebook.
比如把数据导入到 Jupyter Notebook 里
If you weren't provided data,
如果没有人给你提供数据
you need think carefully about what data would be most helpful in
那么你就要认真思考 想想什么数据最能帮你回答问题
answering your questions and then collect them from all the sources available.
然后再尽可能地从各种来源收集数据
Second, you assess your data to identify
第二 你要评估数据
any problems in your data's quality or structure.
找出数据是否有质量或结构的问题
Third, you clean your data.
第三 清理数据
This often involves modifying, replacing,
这一步往往涉及数据的修改、替换
or moving data to ensure that your data set
或移动 目的是尽可能保证数据集
is as high quality and well-structured as possible.
质量高 结构好
This wrangling step is all about getting
整理步骤的目的就在于
the data you need in a form that you can work with.
把你需要的数据处理成便于操作的形式
Sometimes, this step will be really easy and straightforward.
有时候这一步特别简单直接
Other times, it's a little more tricky.
有时候则会有些棘手
Now that you've wrangle your data,
现在你整理好了数据
you'll hopefully have good quality, clean data.
你的数据应该又优质又干净了
Which means, you're ready to explore.
这也就意味着 你可以开始探索了
EDA or exploratory data analysis is about exploring and then augmenting
EDA 也就是探索性数据分析 要做的就是探索并增强数据
your data to maximize the potential of your analyses, visualizations, and models.
从而将分析、可视化界面和模型的潜力最大化
Exploring involves finding patterns in your data,
探索步骤涉及寻找数据模式
visualizing relationships in your data
可视化数据中的相关性
and just building intuition about what you're working with.
以及培养对处理对象的直观认知等
After exploring, you can do things like remove outliers
数据探索完成后 你可以做一些事 如剔除异常数值
and create new and more descriptive features from existing data,
基于既有数据 创建描述性更强的新特征
also known as feature engineering.
即所谓的特征工程
Many times modifying and engineer your data properly and
很多时候恰当地 甚至是创造性地修改并处理数据
even creatively can significantly increase the quality of your analysis.
能够大幅提升你的分析质量
As you become more familiar with your data in this EDA step,
在进行 EDA 的过程中 随着你对数据的日益熟悉
you'll often revisit previous steps.
你会经常返回之前的步骤
For example, you might discover new problems in your data and go back to wrangle them.
比如 你可能在数据中发现了新问题 于是回头重新整理数据
Or you might discover exciting,
或者你可能发现了让人兴奋且出乎意料的模式
unexpected patterns and decide to refine your questions.
并决定修改你的问题
The data analysis process isn't always linear.
数据分析过程并不总是线性的
This exploratory step in particular is very intertwined with the rest of the process.
特别是探索步骤 它与其它步骤密切关联
It's usually where you discover and learn the most about your data.
也往往是你从数据中发现并学到最多的一步
After you've done your exploratory data analysis,
等你完成了探索性数据分析
you want to draw conclusions or even make predictions.
你就需要得出结论 甚至是做出预测
For example, predicting which students will
比如 预测哪个学生的项目会失败
fail a project so you can reach out to those students.
这样你就可以去找他们沟通了
Or predicting which products are most likely
或者预测哪种产品最有可能卖出
to sell so you can start your store appropriately.
以便你针对性地存货
From a data science perspective,
从数据科学的角度来看
this step is typically approached with machine learning or
这一步通常会借助机器学习
inferential statistics that are beyond the scope of this course.
或推断统计学来实现 但本课程不涵盖这两个方面
But there are additional courses on Udacity
不过优达学城有其它课程
they can take on these topics, if you're interested.
涵盖了这两个话题 如果你感兴趣
Those are linked in instructor resources below.
请查看下方讲师注释里的链接
This course will help you form a solid foundation on drawing
本课程是帮你
conclusions from summarizing data with descriptive statistics.
用描述统计学进行数据汇总 为得出结论打下坚实的基础
Finally, you need to communicate your results to others.
最后 你需要同其他人交流成果
This is one of the most important skills you can develop.
这是你可以提升的最重要的技能之一
Your analysis is only as valuable as your ability to communicate it.
你分析的能力有多强 你的分析价值就有多大
You often need to justify and convey meaning in the insights you found.
对于你所得的见解 你经常需要向他人证明并传达其中的意义
Or if your end goal is to build a system,
如果你最终的目标是打造一个系统
like a movie recommender or a news feed ranking algorithm,
比如电影推荐系统或新闻推送排行算法
you usually to share what you've built,
通常你需要同他人分享你的作品
explain how you reach design decisions and report how well it performs.
解释这种设计的决策是如何做出的 并对作品表现进行报告
You can communicate results in many ways.
你有很多方法可以交流成果
Reports, slide decks, blog posts,
如报告、幻灯片、博文、
emails, presentations, or even conversations.
电子邮件、展示、甚至是对话
Regardless of your method of communication,
不管你的交流方法是什么
data visualization will always be very valuable.
将数据可视化总是非常有价值的
So those are the five steps of the data analysis process: question,
以上就是数据分析过程的五大步骤 提出问题、
wrangle, explore, draw conclusions and communicate.
整理数据、探索数据、得出结论以及交流结果
Before jumping into how you go through this process on a real data set in Python,
在开始用 Python 处理真实数据集 向你介绍如何进行数据分析之前
we are going to work on building intuition for each step.
我们将努力培养你对每一步的直观认知